# David Trumble . Jarvis Consulting

My name is David Trumble; a current Software Developer of Jarvis Consulting Group. I have a Diploma in Computer Programming as well as previous industry experience freelancing as both; Full-Stack and WordPress Developer. The software industry is a challenging yet rewarding job scope for myself, it is an opportunity to: have an outlet for my creativity, learn new things, collaborate with like-minded individuals and ultimately work towards something that makes a positive lasting impact.

#### Skills

Proficient: Java, C/C++, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, HTML/CSS/BootStrap, JavaScript, VIM

Competent: SQL Developer, Node.js, Postgres, Heroku, IBM i-series/AS400, PuTTY/FileZilla/WinSCP

Familiar: React, PHP, Python, R, Arduino, MongoDB, SSH/SCP/SFTP, Windows/Powershell, UML

### Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_DavidTrumble

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: This project uses Google Cloud Platform(Compute Engine) to initialize a Virtual Machine with CentOS. Within the Virtual Machine, an instance of Docker is provisioned. A Postgresql instance is then provisioned on Docker. Data is inserted via an automated Bash/Shell script and retrieved from the RDBMS with SQL; which details hardware specifications.

### Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: The Java application uses a bottom-up approach that can CRUD(create, read and delete) tweets from the CLI via the Twitter REST API. A Java library is also implemented to process the Twitter API; as the Twitter API returns data in the form of JSON. Junit and Mockito were used as testing tools, IntelliJ was used as a IDE and source code control was performed through git. Also, Maven was used to package and manage dependencies in conjuction with Spring, then the application was Dockerized and pushed to Docker Hub for easier user consumption.
- JDBC App: This project uses JDBC to establish a connection between the java application and a Postgres database running on a docker container using postgres image to implement CRUD operations on sales order information using DAO patterns. The DAO connects to a local database and performs: creation, reading, updating and deleting through CRUD operations. This project uses Maven Standart Directory Layout. The application uses a psql instance to create, populate and query a database. Also, this project populates an ER diagram with DBeaver. JDBC is used to handle errors and act as connection driver to the psql database. The entirety of the application is allocated on a Docker image.
- Grep App: This application is a Java program to validate regex patterns. The application searches for a text pattern recursively in a given directory and outputs matched lines to a file. This project uses the Maven Standard Directory Layout following the industry standard. Managed with IntelliJ IDE and utilizes Java Regex API, Lambda and Stream API's. Also, SL4J as a logging framework for debug and error information. The grep app is then Dockerized so it's easier for the user to consume.

## **Highlighted Projects**

**3-Band Equalizer** [GitHub]: Virtual Studio Technology - Low Cut, High Cut and Parametric Equalizer with Frequency and Gain control. Technologies include: C++, STL and JUCE Framework.

**Typing Tutor** [GitHub]: Helps users learn typing without looking at keys. Has on-screen keyboard display and highlights keys that are being pressed. Technologies include: Java, JavaFX, Swing, AWT, JDBC and XAMPP.

Weighted Learning - Rock Paper Scissors [GitHub]: Creates a simulation between 2 AI opponents in a game of Rock, Paper, Scissors; then weighs the results to determine future decisions. Technologies include: C++ and STL.

**Quantifying Gravitational Force** [GitHub]: Receive user input then quantifies the Neutrons of Gravitational Force between 2 objects on Earth. Technologies include: C++ and STL.

### **Professional Experiences**

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Serve as a member and lead of the software development team. Facilitate proper design and implementation of software. Provide detailed and innovative design; creating a seamless software

experience. Technologies include: Bash, Postgresql, Docker, Java, JDBC, Git and Maven.

Full-Stack Developer, Freelance - https://stormy-plateau-32984.herokuapp.com/ (2021): Provided Front-End website architecture, user interactions on it's web page and end-to-end service. Also, developed Back-End and managed server functionality; ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones. Technologies include: HTML, CSS, BootStrap, Heroku and Express.js

WordPress Developer, Freelance - https://coast.edwincheungdesign.com/ (2020): Established and guided the websites architecture to ensure high-performance and availability; while creating extra utility functions. Managed and formulated effective, responsive designs and converted them to a working theme as a customizable, open-source eCommerce platform. Technologies include: WordPress, PHP, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

Program Coordinator & Audio Engineer, The Noize Faktory (2014-2019): Prepared and documented all new client contracts, registrations and payments for new and on-going studio services. Instructed individual and group tutorials in: recording, production, theoretical acoustics, music composition, mixing and mastering.

Account Manager & Arrears Account Specialist, Captial One (2008-2009, 2012-2013): Presented, chartered and managed concerns with account holders and employed timely solutions. Determined the validity of client statements and advised client of file procedures; clearly documenting call results and consumer account communications.

Marketing Sales Representative, CanEAST Communications (2009-2010): Developed product-relevant presentations for individuals, families, large groups and businesses. Directed sales inquiries, pricing and information as first point of contact for new and potential customers.

#### Education

Seneca College (2018-2021), Diploma, Computer Programming

Recording Arts Canada (2014-2015), Certificate, Audio Engineering

Seneca College (2012-2013), Certificate, General Arts

Seneca College (2010-2012), Incomplete, Business Administration - Marketing

### Miscellaneous

- 3rd Dan Kukkiwon
- N/A
- Read
- Music
- Exercise